Digital Product Delivery Manager with 12+ years of combined experience in Data Science, R&D and Engineering. Initiated, managed and delivered over 40 data and digital transformation products across Steel manufacturing (UAE, India, Russia), Oil and Gas (US, Russia) and Financial industries (US, Malta) with overall economic benefit >\$20mln.

Portfolio: https://dzorikhin.github.io/portfolio/ GitHub: https://github.com/DZorikhin

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmitry-zorikhin/

## PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Digital Product Delivery Manager**

January 2022 - present

Emirates Steel Arkan, Digital Centre of Excellence - Metals & Mining, Abu Dhabi, UAE

- Managing the team of Data Scientists and Digital Delivery Specialists, promoted from Lead Data Scientist
- Implemented Value-In-Use model (25 models + optimization) resulted in > \$5mIn/year/plant savings
- Created portfolio with over 20 digital and data science products according with Company strategy goals
- Developed Data Product Delivery Framework
- Delivered over 10 data and digital products through internal teams and external partners' network
- Building, deploying, and maintaining advanced analytical and data models in a business setting

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | Timeseries analysis | SQL | Git | Azure | Databricks | Docker | Power BI | ML Ops

Senior Data Scientist May 2021 – December 2021

PwC Malta, Digital Transformation - Financial Services, Malta

- Developed and automated financial statements data extraction tool, processed over 10,000 documents
- Initiated 3 data science projects within Assurance and Tax departments

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | Timeseries analysis | SQL | Power BI

**Senior Data Scientist** 

July 2020 - March 2021

NLMK Group, Digital Transformation - Metals & Mining, Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Managed 4 digital products at MVP/production stage with \$400,000/year overall economic benefit
- Created portfolio with 15 digital and data science products according with Company strategy goals
- Led the group of 6 Data Science contractor teams
- Initiated 2 innovative projects for production upgrade (laser cutting technology, hydrostatic pressure monitoring)

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | Deep Learning | Timeseries analysis | SQL | GitLab | Hadoop | Spark | Docker

Data Scientist June 2019 – July 2020

Advisor Energy, Digital Transformation - Oil & Gas, Houston, USA

- Developed data-driven forecasting model for shale oil & gas production with 95% accuracy
- Prepared 8 US oil & gas shale basin reports covering over 80 E&P assets using quarterly updated data
- Data-driven Net Asset Value models | Type/Decline curves analytics | Reserves | Completions

Tech stack: Python | JavaScript | Classical ML | RNN | Timeseries analysis | AWS | SQL | Power BI | Git | Docker

Lead Data Analyst March 2019 – June 2019

SKB Kontur, Business Analytics – Software Development, Yekaterinburg, Russia

• Saved \$40,000/month as the result of notification services analysis of lead company's product Kontur.Extern

Tech stack: SQL | GitLab | Python | Classical ML

Engineer November 2015 – March 2019

Sakhalin Energy Investment Company Ltd. (Shell and Gazprom JV) - Oil & Gas, Yuzhno-Sakhalinsk, Russia

- Saved \$2mln/well by optimizing well completion timing execution using engineering data model database
- Initiated and got financial approval for joint cloud-based data project for Wells and Subsurface departments
- Reduced CAPEX worth \$50,000/well by optimizing completion string for workover projects

#### **Data and Research Scientist**

November 2009 – August 2014

Ural Federal University | Labfer Ltd. - Science (Optoelectronics, Physics), Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Won and led own grant for scientific research with total amount of funds over \$13,000
- Developed ferroelectric substrates bonding technology for engineering project execution worth \$260,000
- Patent owner "Hysteresis-free High-Temperature Precise Bimorph Actuators" as part of project team

## **EDUCATION**

| MSc Offshore Oil and Gas Engineering  | 2014 – 2015 |
|---|-------------|
| Diploma with Distinction, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UK  |             |
| PhD studies in Computational Physics and Physics of Condensed Matter Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia       | 2013 – 2014 |
| MSc of Engineering and Technology in Innovations Diploma with Distinction, Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia | 2011 – 2013 |
| BSc of Engineering and Technology in Innovations Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia                           | 2007 – 2011 |

# SKILLS, ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS AND RELEVANT CERTIFICATES